Dev Prajapati

d@praj.co.uk 07397973811 London praj.co.uk linkedin.com/in/devpraj github.com/prajz

Dedicated programmer with a zeal for problem solving. Previous experiences have allowed me to gain valuable insight into software development, tasks, and responsibilities as both a leader and a team member.

Education

Computer Science BSc/University of Bath

(September 2021 – June 2024) Predicted: First Class Honours

Modules taken: (Year 1) 2:1

Artificial Intelligence – Learn and apply AI techniques using unsupervised

and supervised ML algorithms

Computer Systems Architecture 1 – Understanding and experimenting with some of the

fundamental issues operating within the layered

model of computer architectures

Computer Systems Architecture 2 – Understanding of the computer architecture for

stand-alone and distributed or networked systems

Principles of Programming 1 & 2 - Applying programming paradigms such as Object

Oriented and learning good coding etiquette using

Python, C and Java

Discrete mathematics & databases - Using mathematical concepts such as set theory,

number theory and logic and SQL queries to

access databases

Mathematics for Computation – Use of matrices, vector and algebra to reinforce

understanding of core mathematical concepts

Software Processes and modelling - Applied different software development models

such as AGILE and waterfall

Modules taking: (Year 2)

Machine Learning, Foundation of Computation, Data Structures & Algorithms, Functional Programming, Fundamentals of Visual Computing, Experimental Systems Project, Comparative programming languages, Human-computer Interaction and User Experience

A Levels/Wembley High Technology College

(September 2019 - June 2021)

• Maths, Further Maths, Physics; A*, A*, A respectively

GCSE/Wembley High Technology College

(September 2014 – June 2019)

 14 GCSEs (all between grades 9-7) including 9s in Mathematics, Biology, Chemistry and Physics

Work Experience

Teaching Assistant / Free-lance tutoring

(September 2018 - present)

- Organised and Co-ordinated one on one/group sessions with GCSE ComputerScience and A level Mathematics students.
- Helped struggling students learn complex concepts by breaking the problem down and re-explaining the solution and their mistakes.
- Marking students work and providing useful yet concise feedback, ensuring the emphasis on efficiency.

Project Manager (Shadowing), Perlego, London

(August 2019 - August 2019)

- Delivered a presentation to the department using HTML and CSS on the Agile methodology, explaining the key differences between the current used methodology (Waterfall).
- Was introduced to implementations such as scrums and Trello

Team Member/Shift Manager, Tim Hortons, London

(May 2022 - November 2022)

- Managed incoming delivery of stock weekly
- Trained new team members efficiently whilst maintaining high level of output allowing advancement into a further role
- Worked well under extreme pressure as the store was always busy and was often understaffed
- Balanced work with university projects on the side which built organisational and time management skills

Cadet Corporal, RAFAC, London

(September 2017 - March 2020)

 Providing training for younger cadets, presenting different lessons (i.e., map reading, RAF history, etc.), gaining skills like first aid, experiencing flying, gliding, canoeing, going to different camps (e.g., RAF Cranwell, fieldcraft) working together as a team with other Cadet NCOs (Non-Commissioned Officer) to plan out different working nights

Personal Projects and Achievements

Smart Garden - 2nd Place

- Design and developing a smart gardening tool with Arduinos and sensors for water level and UV light, achieving 2nd of 50 projects.
- Functional automatic and manual modes allowing plants to receive all nutrients required to grow optimally
- Adapted to any unforeseeable events and made sure the set deadlines were met.

Interactive Campus map - Team Leader

- Lead the development of the project as manager (group of 7 people) applying the skills I learnt from my previous work experience at Perlego
- The entire Design and Development process was split into small sections which I assigned to team members and myself to ensure fair working standards.

Website development - Free lancer

- Created websites using HTML, CSS and JS React
- Helped out small start-ups by analysing already existing websites and giving constructive criticism to improve their brand

iSpendify - Expense Tracker (iOS development)

- Taught myself SwiftUI concepts such as CoreData and fetching data from other APIs in iOS
- Used this knowledge to create a practical app which tracks spending and depicts it visually and concisely with the use of Swift Charts

Technical skills

Java, Python, C, SwiftUI, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MSOffice